when we produce we like to experiment a
lot we make everything in our living
room we like to experiment a lot
produce with a lot of layers try and
find weird sounds you don't normally
hear in music
so i'm going to show you how we produced
one of our songs all right
so me and jack were pretty uninspired we
kind of had writer's block
and then all of a sudden this happened
we heard a knock at the door
and we didn't really care who was at the
door no we just cared about the sound of
that knock
but play it again so we took that knock
and we pitched it up an octave
it sounded like this
kind of like a snare and then we took
that same knock and we pitched it down
an octave
and that sounded like a kick drum so
then we took that kick and that snare
and we laid it down on the beat
all right it sounded like this
[Music]
yeah okay good start then we added a
little hi-hat
[Music]
all right that out of the bounce
so right now it's straight so i'll tell
you what straight it it's
[Laughter]
but we wanted it to swing we want it to
be swung okay
that sounds like this
bring the beat back in your hair it's a
little more unique sounding
[Music]
all right next we added a bass line and
we wanted something that was kind of
angry and evil sounding all right
something like this
then we added piano that sounded like
[Music]
this
so right now it's a little bit fast i
feel like if we slow it down it's going
to sound more like an ajr song
can we hear that
even more cool bring the music back in
yeah better
then we added some trumpets
[Music]
little reggae
then we added some tom drums like this
all right we were almost there there was
one more step we wanted a voice to kind
of
announce here's the chorus and so me and
jack were on the subway
one day and we heard this stand clear of
the closing doors please
we said i wish we could get that guy to
be on our song
and then he said you can and we said
really
and he said sure i have nothing else to
do
oh okay can you can you say it say what
can we hear the line the line from our
song can we hear it
hear what the line from our song the
line you say in our song can we hear it
oh
you mean this here we go
[Music]
i get up i get down and i'm jumping
around
and the rumpus from work is so
comfortable now
been a hell of a ride but i'm thinking
it's time
to grow
so i got an apartment across from the
park but quite in my fridge still i'm
not feeling grown
been a hell of a ride but i'm thinking
it's time
to go here we go
[Music]
[Applause]
i feel like i'm gonna
[Music]
but i'm thinking it's time to grow
metronomes
[Music]
here we go
is
[Music]
let's go
so put your best face on everybody
pretend you
know this song everybody coming
let's go out with the bang here we go
[Music]
here we go